So you're planning a trip to see Mount Fuji,
but you're not sure where to start.
What is there to do?
How many days do you need?
And how do you even get there?
Well, I'm here to help.
I recently visited Kawaguchiko, and I'll
walk you through everything
you need to know.
From what to do, where to eat, and how
to go about planning your visit.
So without further delays,
let's get into it.
From Tokyo, it only takes around 2 hours
to get to Fujikawaguchiko.
This makes the area ideal for a
day trip or even longer.
Mount Fuji is bordered by 5 lakes, also
known as the Fuji 5 lakes.
The most developed and popular of
the lakes is Kawaguchiko.
So how many days do you need
to visit Kawaguchiko?
Since it's not too far from Tokyo,
Kawaguchiko can be done as either
a day trip or even an
overnight trip.
A day trip is ideal if you're only sticking
to exploring the Kawaguchiko area.
But personally, I think Kawaguchiko is
best experienced over 2 days.
This gives you more time to explore
Kawaguchiko in depth and open
the doors for exploring
other nearby areas.
It also gives you more chances to spot Fuji
since Fuji is notoriously shy at times.
But more importantly, you'll
have more time
to relax and explore at a
more leisurely pace.
Either way, you can't go wrong with either
a day trip or a slightly longer visit.
There are a number of ways to
get to Kawaguchiko,
such as trains or renting a
car, but I personally
find the easiest way is via
the expressway bus.
In a little under 2 hours, you can go
directly from stations such as
Tokyo or Shinjuku to Kawaguchiko.
And if the weather is clear, you can
even see Fuji along the way.
You can reserve seats one
month in advance
via booking websites such
as highway-buses.jp.
Let's take a closer look at
the Kawaguchiko area.
Everything is centered around the
Kawaguchiko station, which is
where you'll arrive.
It's the main transportation hub for
buses in the Mount Fuji area.
For the best areas to stay
in, I recommend
staying near the Kawaguchiko
station for most
for most people.
It's the most convenient in terms of
transportation, and you'll find
plenty of restaurants and
accommodations to choose from.
But if you want the best view of Fuji from
your hotel room, then you'll have to go
along the northern shores of the lake.
Just be aware that it's less
convenient since
it's further away from the
station and you'll
rely more on buses to get
around, and they
do tend to get crowded during
peak tourist seasons
For my visit, I chose a hotel
called Rakuyu.
We stayed in a lovely Japanese traditional
room with a view over Lake Kawaguchi.
The hotel is only a 15-minute
walk from the
station, which made it a great
base for exploration
of Kawaguchiko.
This video has been sponsored by Saily.
Saily is an e-sim app that offers affordable
data plans ideal for travel.
Whether you're exploring Japan,
eating street food in South Korea,
or relaxing in a hot
or relaxing in a hot spring in Iceland,
Saily's got your back.
With data plans in over 200 destinations,
there's almost always a data
plan that works for you.
And it's super easy to get started.
Simply install the app in
your phone, choose
a suitable data plan, and
within minutes of
activating the e-sim, you got data, and
you're now ready to start exploring.
And if something doesn't quite work, their
24-7 chat support is here to help.
Nothing beats having the
right data plan by
your side so you can focus
on enjoying your travels
Get an exclusive 15% discount
on Saily data plans.
Just download the app and use the code
ALLANSU at checkout or simply
scan this QR code.
Saily has been a long-term
sponsor of this channel,
helping me continue making these videos.
If you'd like to support what I do, the
best way is to check out my sponsors.
It really does make a difference.
Thanks again to Saily, and now let's
get back to the video.
We begin our first day by exploring
Kawaguchiko and the nearby area
surrounding the lake.
To get around, there are
buses that covers
the surrounding area such
as the Kawaguchiko sightseeing bus,
which covers the northern
and eastern shores of Kawaguchiko.
Just use an IC card when you board,
like any other regular bus.
However, in my opinion, renting a bike is
the best way to explore Kawaguchiko.
There are plenty of bike rental shops around
the station, so you can't miss them.
I recommend spending a little
extra on electric bikes.
Just make getting up on hills or running
around the lake way easier.
With our bikes, we begin to make our way
towards the famous Chureito Pagoda.
But first, we make a quick stop along the
way at the Honcho Street,
known for its street view of Mt. Fuji.
This is a very popular photo spot, and
unfortunately, due to the amount
of people here trying to
get their photo, the town had to appoint
staff here to stop people from
blocking traffic.
So I encourage everyone
who visits here to
be respectful of the staff and locals and
don't block traffic.
There are plenty of other
places where you
can get a similar view of
Fuji, such as the
side street that's just a
few minutes away,
or even this spot, just
nearby Kawaguchiko station,
all without crowds.
Next up, we finally arrive
at Chureito Pagoda.
It's here you can get the classic view of
the Pagoda with Mt. Fuji
in the background.
It's a very popular spot, and it's a little
bit of a climb to get up to the Pagoda.
Due to the number of people
here, you could
sometimes expect to wait a
little while before
reaching the viewing platform.
After the Pagoda, we bike back towards
the lake to find some lunch.
One of my favorite meals during my time
in Kawaguchiko was at Pizzeria Onda.
They serve legit Neapolitan pizzas, and
you know the owner takes
his craft seriously
when he's donning a Napoli shirt.
The service can be a bit slow when it gets
busy, but the pizzas are so worth it.
If you love a good pizza, then it's definitely
a place worth checking out.
After lunch, we take things
a little slower.
We decide to bike along Lake Kawaguchi,
stopping wherever we wanted,
especially when there
was a nice view of Mt. Fuji.
Biking around the lake was arguably my favorite
part of visiting Kawaguchiko.
There are endless viewpoints
along the shore
where you can just pull over
and take in the view.
So if I haven't said it already,
I highly recommend
renting a bike when
exploring Kawaguchiko.
If you want to try something a little bit different,
you can even rent one of these
swan boats and head out onto the lake for
a more unique experience
of Lake Kawaguchi.
As we continue to bike along the lake, we make
our way to Oishi Park, a free public
park on the north shore
of Lake Kawaguchi.
It's known for its seasonal flower
displays and views of Mt. Fuji.
I recommend grabbing an ice cream, taking
a walk, and enjoying the scenery.
As the sun starts to set, we make our way
back towards the station to
find some dinner.
We end up at a restaurant called
Fuji Tempura Itaten.
As the name implies, a restaurant that specializes
in tempura and fried food items.
The food here was solid, and it was a
satisfying way to end our first
day in Kawaguchiko.
On our second day, we head out of the
Kawaguchiko area and jump on a
bus to Lake Yamanaka, the
largest of the Fuji 5 lakes.
The lake has a slightly different feel
compared to Kawaguchiko.
It's more open and less crowded,
because of its size you get a wider,
more panoramic view of Mount Fuji.
The lake is also known as Swan Lake, and
you'll often see swans hanging
out along the shore.
For lunch, we stop by at a
cafe called The Park.
They're known for their souffle pancakes,
and you get an incredible
view of Mount Fuji
as a backdrop for your pancakes.
After lunch, we take the
bus, and continue
to Oshino Hakkai, a small
village known for
its eight ponds, all fed by snow
melt for Mount Fuji.
The water here is incredibly
pure, filtered
naturally through the layers
of volcanic rock over decades
Because of that, the ponds are extremely
clear, with reflections of
Fuji on a clear day.
The place can't get a bit touristy, but
I think it's still worth a visit.
We then make our way back
towards Kawaguchiko,
for our final meal
before heading back to Tokyo
Hoto is a hearty noodle soup made with
thick, flat noodles, almost
like udon, but with a
softer, more rustic texture.
It's served in a miso-based broth, packed
with seasonal vegetables like
pumpkin, mushroom,
carrots, and cabbage.
There's usually no meat in this
traditional version.
It's simple, filling, and very much
a countryside-style dish.
Before leaving Kawaguchiko,
we get a quick shot
of a Lawson with Mount Fuji
in the background.
This is not the Lawson right next to the station,
which usually is pretty crowded.
And that wraps up our trip
to Kawaguchiko.
If you're looking for more
things to do or
just some other options, here's
a short list.
The Fuji Panoramic Roadway offers panoramic
views over Kawaguchiko.
Fuji-Q Highland, if you're
into theme parks,
Lake Motosu, popular for camping
and stargazing,
and finally, Kawaguchiko Music
Forest Museum,
a compact theme park and museum
centered around
self-playing musical instruments.
And that's it!
It's a simple trip, but one of the most
rewarding you can do from Tokyo.
If you're playing a Japan trip,
I'll definitely
recommend adding Kawaguchiko
to your itinerary.
It's a great way to get out of the city
and enjoy arguably the country's
most iconic landmark.
I hope this video gave you a good idea on
how to go about planning
a trip to see Mount Fuji.
If you have any questions,
leave them in the comments below
and I'll get back to you.
Thanks for watching,
this is Allan.
I'll see you guys in the next one.